# **Grigorii Orlov**

Lead/Senior Frontend Developer London, UK. Sponsorship Certificate Required gri-go-riy@outlook.com +44 785 3018022 linkedin.com/in/grigoriy-orlov

T-shaped, responsible, and collaborative Software Engineer and Team Lead. 9+ years of experience in development in startups, consultancies, and product companies. Advanced skills in frontend development, an expert in JavaScript, various frontend frameworks, and libraries. Comprehensive knowledge of Java and backend utilities. Passionate about user experience and clear software architecture.

#### Technical Skills

**Languages** TypeScript, JavaScript, Java, Golang

Frameworks & libs ReactJS, NextJS, Svelte, Effector, Recoil, Redux, OSM, ExpressJS, NestJS, WebRTC, Spring

# Professional Experience

#### **Authentise LTD**

## Senior Frontend engineer

Mar 2021 - Present

Created a SaaS product to manage 3D printing infrastructure for big companies (such as Boing, Xerox, etc)

- Led mobile application development based on React Native
- Migrated frontend application from Redux and Rest API to GraphQL and Apollo Client which decreased page loading time up to 80%
- Implemented code splitting strategy
- Developed a 3D printing visualization module based on three.js
- Designed user stories, and wireframes, made UX improvements
- Implemented simultaneous data processing features which allowed which reduced time-to-first interaction time up to 90%

#### S7 TechLab

### Head of Frontend department

Dec 2021 - Apr 2022

S7 TechLab is the innovation center of the big airline company

- Developed low-code visual SPA constructor based on the top of Nextjs/React which reduce pilot project creation time up to 40%
- · Managed subordinates, participated in scrum activities, consulted colleagues, evaluated risks
- Developed and implemented Design System and UI library with Unit tests and documentation based on Storybook
- Reviewed 7 projects, made several major architectural improvements
- Designed frontend architecture for new projects
- Led and influenced software engineering best practices within teams for the full software development life cycle, including documentation, design, coding standards, code reviews, building, testing, deployment, etc.
- Mentored junior developers, helped teammates to improve their skills
- Acted as technical lead and key developer on 3 projects

### **Natera Inc**

## Senior & Lead Frontend Engineer

Dec 2019 - Dec 2021

Developed a flexible platform to allow customers to gather and analyze information about counterparties

- Implemented a task estimation methodology that allowed to evaluate sprint performance with an accuracy of >95%
- Developed various tools & features for simultaneous data modification
- · Organized unit and e2e testing in the project
- Worked close with UX designer to organize UX research and user testing
- Managed subordinates, participated in scrum activities, consulted colleagues, evaluated risks
- Implemented CI/CD for the frontend part of the application based on GitLab CI
- Developed and implemented a Design System with Unit tests and documentation based on Storybook with 200+ components
- · Designed frontend architecture
- Mentored junior developers, helped teammates to improve their skills

Led a team of 5 members

# **Diginavis**

# Senior Software Engineer

Nov 2018 - Dec 2019

Developed a high-loaded management system for unmanned vehicles

- Designed and developed a scalable, real-time ReactJS application
- Improved performance from 10 to 60 FPS for the most loaded parts of the app
- Implemented CI/CD for the frontend part of the application
- Developed and implemented multi-domain OAuth-based authentication
- Developed and implemented a JS library for the visualization of on-map data
- Coordinated the teamwork of 3 developers

#### **ITeco**

# Software Engineer & Senior Software Engineer

Apr 2016 - Nov 2018

Developed and successfully delivered SPA (part of a complex enterprise solution) for letting clients book deposit boxes online for one of the biggest banks in Russia

- Developed and implemented a module for remote printing
- Created 30+ new components for the internal UI library
- Achieved 90+% in test coverage on the Backend side
- Implemented integration with other banking modules and flows
- Made several major CI/CD improvements which allowed to reduce deployment time from 27 to 10 minutes
- Interviewed 30 candidates and mentored 4 junior engineers

#### Fox-ST & other web-studios

## Lead Web Developer & CEO

Sep 2012 - Feb 2016

Established a web-studio focused on smart solutions for small and medium businesses

- Led the development of Web and Mobile applications. Crated 30+ apps in total
- Developed a custom CRM with WooCommerce, OpenCart and SIP integration
- Developed and delivered a solution to allow local anti-drug department handle incoming citizens' applications
- Delivered innovative technical solutions to improve business outcomes
- Implemented integration with third-party APIs

Education\_

**Master of Computer Science** 

Moscow Institute of Physics and Technology, 2016